There is nothing more human than the will to survive.
Ex Machina is a drama, science fiction film directed by Alex Garland.
Caleb, a coder at the world's largest internet company, wins a competition to spend a week at a
private mountain retreat belonging to Nathan, the reclusive CEO of the company.
But when Caleb arrives at the remote location he finds that he will have to participate in a strange and fascinating experiment in
which he must interact with the world's first true artificial intelligence, housed in the body of a beautiful robot girl.
Caleb, played by Domhnall Gleeson.
Ava, played by Alicia Vikander.
Nathan, played by Oscar Isaac.
Kyoko, played by Sonoya Mizuno.
Jay, played by Corey Johnson.
Lily, played by Claire Selby.
Ex Machina is a 2014  science fiction film, written and
directed by Alex Garland in his directorial debut.
It stars Domhnall Gleeson, Alicia Vikander, and Oscar Isaac.
It follows a programmer who is invited by his CEO to administer the
Turing test to an intelligent female humanoid robot.
Ex Machina premiered at the BFI Southbank on 16 December 2014.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 21 January 2015, by Universal Pictures
International, and in the United States on 10 April 2015, by A24.
It grossed over $36.8 million worldwide on a $15 million budget.
Ex Machina received acclaim for its visual effects, screenplay and performances.
At the 88th Academy Awards, it won Best Visual Effects and
Garland was nominated for Best Original Screenplay.
It earned five nominations at the 69th British Academy Film Awards, including Best Actress in a Supporting Role for Vikander and Best
Original Screenplay for Garland, and Vikander was also nominated for Best Supporting Actress at the 73rd Golden Globe Awards.
Ex Machina has been cited as among the best films of the 2010s.
The film explores themes of android, dancing,
friendship, man vs machine, distrust.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.